本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
尤瑟陛下  有访客
King Uther, there is a visitor.
她不肯透露姓名
She won't give her name.
你是何人
Who are you?
摩根
Morgan.
父王
Father.
你那贱人还活着
Your whore still lives.
要尊重你的母后
You'll respect your mother.
是继母
Stepmother.
你为何来此
Why are you here?
我回来是想告诉你  我原谅了你
I've come home and I want to offer you forgiveness.
原谅我什么
For what?
原谅你害死我的母亲
For the death of my mother,
只为立这贱人为后
so you could install this whore.
原谅你流放了我  以便堵住我的嘴
And for banishing me so I'd be silenced.
我送走你  是为了让你得到教育
I sent you away for an education.
在修道院待了十五年  我学到的
Fifteen years in a nunnery, I learned more
远超乎你的想象
than you can imagine.
父王  我是你唯一的孩子
Father, I'm your only child.
你为何不肯欢迎我回家呢
Why wouldn't you welcome me home?
你脱离我的指引太久了
You've lived too long without my guidance.
这里已经不是你的家了
This isn't your home now.
我也不再有你这个女儿了
And I no longer have a daughter.
别抛弃我  父王
Don't turn your back on me, Father!
这里不欢迎你  摩根
You're not welcome Morgan.
后会无期
Goodbye.
伊格兰  别理会她
Igraine, leave her.
尤瑟  尤瑟
Uther! Uther!
尤瑟
Uther?
尤瑟  你怎么了
Uther! What's wrong?
救命  快来人救救他  尤瑟
Help! Somebody help him! Uther!
帮帮我们
Help us!
闪开
Out of my way!
打开大门
Open the gates!
救他  救他
Help him! Help him!
快送陛下回寝宫  快
Take the King to his chambers! Now!
哈利路亚  曾当以色列出离埃及
Alleluia dilexi quoniam exaudiet
出自《圣经·旧约》《圣咏集》》
雅各伯家离开蛮夷时
dominus vocem orationis meae.
犹大成了上主的圣所...
Quia inclinavit aurem...
不管你有什么魔法  快用出来吧
Whatever powers you have, use them now!
尤瑟  你大限将至
Uther, you're going to die.
这药毒性太强
The poison was too strong.
签个名
Put your hand to this.
为了大不列颠和那个男孩
For Briton and the boy.
他的时代结束了
His time is done.
梅林
Merlin!
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第一集』
翻译  大卫熊
翻译  小舞
翻译  泰斯
翻译  苏小黛
时间轴  波多而死机
时间轴  小猫
校对  苏小黛
后期  WiLL
特效  WiLL
中转  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
太初有道[拉丁语]
In principio-erat-verbum.
太初有道
In the beginning was the Word.
道就是
And the Word was--
真美啊
God, yes.
这可不是拉丁语课
This isn't Latin study.
对  但这绝对是种崇拜
No, but it is definitely worship.
亚瑟
Arthur!
不会吧
It can't be!
你这混蛋
You bastard!
凯  听着  她说你们两个结束了
Kay, listen-she said you two were over!
亚瑟  我可没那么说
Arthur! No, I did not.
多谢帮忙
Thanks a lot.
住手  你们两个都住手
Stop! Stop it! Both of you!
我真该杀了你
I should kill you.
你怎么找到我们的
How did you even find us?
我知道你会把姑娘们带到什么地方
I know where you bring your girls.
现在连我的姑娘也被你带来了
And now mine, too.
穿上衣服  有人让我来找你  有访客
Get dressed. I was sent to find you. There's a visitor.
跟我有啥关系
What's that got to do with me?
这样很不好  我知道
It's bad. I know.
我不该那么做  我没好好考虑
I shouldn't have done it. I wasn't thinking.
不  你考虑了
No, you were thinking.
你在考虑  "如果被抓到"
You were thinking, if I get caught,
"我可以靠这张嘴来摆脱困境"
I can talk my way out of this.
那是个错误  我们有些忘乎所以
It was a mistake. We got carried away-
两次
twice.
闭嘴  拜托  闭嘴
Shut up. Please, just shut up.
有时候事情自然而然就发生了
Sometimes these things happen.
就好像她是克利欧佩特拉  你是凯撒
It's like she's Cleopatra, you're Caesar,
克利欧佩特拉: 即埃及艳后
她与凯撒及安东尼间的多角恋情请自行搜索
而我是马克·安东尼
and I'm Mark Antony.
不  你真不是
No. You're really not-at all.
不能让一个女人阻碍了我们的关系
We can't let a woman come between us.
是不是  兄弟
Can we, brother?
对你来说  一切都唾手可得
Everything comes easy for you.
你难道不心存感恩吗
Don't you appreciate it.
怎么了
What's going on?
母亲
Mother?
父亲
Father?
他来了
He's here.
你就是那个男孩
So you're the boy.
我是亚瑟  你是谁
I'm Arthur. Who are you?
他叫梅林
His name is Merlin-
这里不欢迎他
and he's not welcome here!
那就让他打道回府
Then he'll be on his way!
-把剑放下  凯  -不
- Put down your sword, Kay. - No!
照我说的做  孩子
Do as you're told, boy!
谁能跟我解释一下  这是怎么回事
Will someone explain what is happening here?
国王死了  被谋杀的
The King is dead. Murdered.
那又如何
So?
尤瑟在没有正统子嗣的情况下死了
Uther died with no legitimate son.
这跟我们有什么关系
What's that got to do with us?
和他们无关  你是尤瑟的儿子
Not them. You-are Uther's son.
不
No.
我的父母就站在这里
My parents are standing here.
告诉他  告诉他啊
Tell him. Tell him.
他说的是事实  亚瑟
He's telling the truth, Arthur.
不可能  这怎么可能
He can't be. How can he be?
你不到一周大的时候  梅林把你送来这里
Merlin brought you to us when you were less than a week old.
我们发誓会照顾你
We swore to look after you.
什么
What?
国王已死
The King is dead.
国王万岁
Long live the King.
收回你的谎话  离开这里
Take your lies and get out!
亚瑟  亚瑟  把剑给我
Arthur, Arthur, give me the blade.
把剑给我
Give me the blade.
你告诉他这是怎么回事
You tell him how this happened.
给他讲他的身世
You tell him the story of his birth.
细节不重要
The details aren't important.
对他来说很重要
They are to him!
亚瑟  我早该告诉你的
Arthur, I should've told you before.
我很抱歉  儿子
I'm-I'm so sorry, son.
今晚好好休息
Rest tonight.
明天  我们出发
Tomorrow, we leave.
她在哪
Where is she?
伊格兰夫人一直在她的寝宫服丧
Lady Igraine remains in mourning in her chamber.
其他人呢
And the men?
大多数都走了
Most are gone.
谁下的命令
On whose authority?
梅林
Merlin's.
就在你父王去世的当晚
The night after your father's death
他的战士们收拾行装  离开了这里
his warriors packed up their belongings and left.
我们会找到自己的战士
Then we'll move on our own.
更勇猛  更强大
Better and stronger.
我们
We?
你现在听命于我
You answer to me now.
谢谢
Thank you.
把那些旗帜扯下来
Pull down those banners!
没收所有的武器  叫厨房的人动起来
Confiscate all the weapons and someone find the kitchens!
我饿死了
I'm bloody starving.
大门为你敞开  大人
The doors are open to you, my Lord.
不必动用武力
There's no need for force.
召唤我的人就是你吗
Are you the one who summoned me?
我是尤瑟的女儿  唯一的继承人
I'm Uther's daughter and sole heir:
摩根·彭德拉根
Morgan Pendragon.
就在我们对话的同时
Even as we speak,
我的人正在屠杀那些仍忠于尤瑟的人
my men are slaughtering all those still loyal to Uther.
你为何把我召集到此
Why would you call me here?
寻求结盟
To offer an alliance.
与谁结盟
Who with?
我
Me.
你
You?
哪有比你更好的人选  洛特国王
Who better than you, King Lot,
我父亲最强大的对手
my father's strongest opponent.
我不吃奉迎这一套
I am immune to flattery.
但收到邀请  你还是来了
And yet you came when asked.
你没什么能作为筹码
You've nothing to offer me.
我拥有这城堡
I hold this castle.
我可以把你从上到下一刀劈开
I could split you from your gut to your throat
同样能夺取城堡
and still take it.
你不会那么愚蠢
You're cleverer than that.
是吗
Am I?
杀了我  你不过成为又一个军阀
Kill me and you're just another warlord
又多占有一座城池
taking yet another castle.
但若我们能联手
But if we stand together-
我独来独往
I stand alone.
若我们结盟
If we forge a union,
那我们便能统一整个王国
we'd have the strength to unite the realm.
成为国王与女王
As King and Queen.
这里已经有一位女王了
There is already a Queen within these walls.
我娶了她同样能占有尤瑟的王座
I could take her and still sit on Uther's throne.
她将被驱除出境
She's to be exiled.
她已被驱逐了吗
Oh, is she now?
没错
Yes.
你对你的计划信心十足啊
You're very confident in your plans.
的确
I am.
你为何如此特别
What makes you so special?
你敢靠近  我就杀了你
Come near me, I'll kill you.
没必要如此虚张声势
Don't issue empty threats.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
我熟知尤瑟·彭德拉根
I knew Uther Pendragon.
他临死时  我相伴在侧
I was at his side when he died.
国王亲笔签名  加盖印玺的遗嘱
The King's will, signed by his own hand, bearing his seal,
证明了你的出身
attesting to your birth.
这是你父亲的
This was your father's.
拿着
Take it.
你降生后  我就把你带到了这里
When you were born, I took you and brought you here.
你有着国王的血脉  但尤瑟实乃一介莽夫
You may be of King's blood but Uther was a barbarian.
在这里成长  会使你更为出色
Acing you here made you so much more.
我告诉埃克特该如何抚养你  教育你
I told Ector how to raise and educate you.
他发誓要保护你安全成长
He swore to always keep you safe.
他们把你养育得很好
They raised you well.
或许好过头了
Perhaps too well.
为什么  为什么需要我
Why? Why do you need me?
凡事自有定数
Everything in time.
我有时也好奇他们为什么更偏爱你
I sometimes wondered why they doted more on you.
你总是被保护得很好
You're always got away with so much.
不是这样
It was never like that.
一直是这样
It's always been like that.
只是你从未发觉
You've just never seen it.
你习惯了只要你一微笑
You're used to the world falling at your feet
全世界就都会为你倾倒
the moment you smile.
不过没关系
But it's all right.
这就解释得通了
This makes sense of it.
他们待你如掌上明珠
They treated you like you were special.
因为你的确独一无二
Because you are.
你总算承认了
At last you finally admit it.
听着  一切都不会改变
Hey, this doesn't change anything.
你仍然是我的弟弟
You're still my brother.
仍然是惹人厌的淘气包
And you're still infuriating.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
我不能这样一走了之  这是我的家
I can't just leave! This is my home.
这里是我所熟知的一切
This is what I know. Here.
但是你有着更好的选择
But what you're being offered is better.
冲锋陷阵  统领江山
Going to battle, leading the land.
这是所有男人的梦想
It's what every man dreams of.
不  这只是你的梦想
No, it's what you dream of.
我们其他人只梦想着姑娘们
The rest of us dream about girls.
你以为领袖就不能挑选姑娘了吗
You think a leader won't get his choice of girls?
为何不接受这样的命运呢
Why shouldn't it be your destiny?
换做是我  我会去
If it was me, I'd go-
马上就去
in an instant.
看来  你决定了
So, you're coming.
我没说我相信你
I'm not saying I believe you.
我只想亲眼去看看
It's just I want to see it for myself.
你已经准备好了
You're ready.
为什么以前不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我怕会失去你
I was afraid of losing you.
因为你是我的儿子
Because you are my son.
你永远都是我的母亲
You'll always be my mother.
我就把他托付给你了
I place him in your care.
你必须保护好他
You keep him safe.
我保证
You have my word.
这是你注定的使命
It's what you were born for.
也是我们培养你的目的
It's what we've guided you for.
记住我教你的一切
You remember what I taught you.
做决定时  要开动脑筋
When you make decisions, you use this
结合内心的想法
in conjunction with this.
决不能用下半身思考
And you never use this!
我会努力记住的
I'll try and remember that.
没有比你更好的父亲了
No son ever had a better father.
我希望你明白
I-I want you to know-
我明白  我明白
I know, I know, I know.
我爱你
I love you.
你们已为我付出了所有
You've given me everything my entire life
我无颜再要求更多
and I feel guilty asking for anything more.
但我需要凯
But-I need Kay.
我想要他跟我一起走
I want him with me.
当然  当然
Yes, yes!
无论怎样  我都无法独自面对
Whatever this is, I can't do it without you.
我们还以为你不会要求呢
We were thought you'd never ask.
兄弟同心  其利断金
Together, you're stronger.
是时候了
It's time.
叫我的名字
Say my name!
摩根
Morgan!
我将是何人
Who will I be?
人民的女王
Queen of the realm!
你能否成为我称职的国王
Are you fit to be my King?
你知道我行
You know I am!
你能给予我什么
What will you give me?
至死不渝的忠诚
Undying loyalty!
发誓忠诚
Swear your fealty!
你先发誓
Swear yours to me!
发誓
Swear it!
我发誓
I swear!
以何之名
On what-
-以我的誓言  -没错
- My oath.  - Yes!
以我的生命
My life!
很好
Yes!
还有你的鲜血
And your blood!
我的鲜血
My blood!
你都是从哪儿学的
Where did you learn that, huh?
父亲一死
Your father dies,
你就流放自己的母亲
and you banish your own mother from her home.
够冷血
Impressive.
是继母
Stepmother.
我是尤瑟唯一的血脉
I'm the only one of Uther's blood.
他的城堡  他的王国都该是我的
His castle and realm should be mine.
于是你就召唤了我  尤瑟最大的死敌
So you summon me, Uther's worst enemy.
你提出与我结盟  接着又引诱了我
You propose an alliance and then seduce me, even
全然不顾你父亲尸骨尚且未寒
as your father's body cools.
你的勃勃野心没有尽头吗
Is there no end to your ambition?
你这是抱怨吗
Are you complaining?
不
No.
只是好奇
Just curious.
女王总是需要一位国王
A queen still requires a king.
没错
Yes.
我们一起将统领整个王国
Together, we'll unite the realm.
没错
Yes.
我去亲自打发她上路
I'll set her on the way myself.
好
Yes.
这样挺适合你的
It suits you up there.
你要去哪儿
Where will you go?
你父亲的盟友会给予我安身之处
Your father had plenty of allies who'll give me space.
还有何事  还是你只是来幸灾乐祸的
Was there anything else, or did you just come to gloat?
我来感激上苍让你活着离开这里
Just give thanks you're leaving here alive.
我从未伤害过你
I did nothing to harm you.
没错  夫人  你从未做过任何事
Indeed, my Lady, you did nothing.
我母亲被害时  你无动于衷
You did nothing when my mother was murdered,
这样你便能取而代之
so that you could take her place.
父王流放我时  你也毫无作为
And you did nothing when my father banished me.
王后无权干涉国王的决定
No queen questions her king!
我以为之前已对你鄙视至极了  没想到此刻更甚
And I thought my opinion of you couldn't get any lower.
一路平安
Safe travels!
背信弃义的国度
The land is treacherous.
我有梅林的口信
I bring a message from Merlin.
梅林  他想怎样
Merlin? What does he want?
他请您去卡米洛特的古城堡
He asks you attend Uther's son
迎接尤瑟的儿子
at the ancient castle of Camelot.
尤瑟的儿子
Uther's son?
我只是原话转告
That's what I was told to deliver.
他有个儿子
He has a son.
我才是王位真正的继承人
I have the only true claim to the throne.
这是梅林的把戏
This is Merlin's game.
那我们就奉陪到底
So, we'll play with him.
如果你对我的身世负有责任
If you were responsible for my birth,
那我理应更多的了解你的身份
I deserve to know more about who you are.
别再问我是谁  好好想想你的身份
Stop asking about me and think about who you are.
你真是巫师吗
Are you really a sorcerer?
我能做到他人认为不可能的事
I can do things others believe impossible.
这算所谓的巫术吗
Is that sorcery?
那试试啊  证明给我看
Go on then. Show me. Prove it to me.
你带我翻山越岭  却什么都不告诉我
You pull me from one coast to the other and you tell me nothing!
你问我为何需要你
You asked me why I need you.
我曾预见过未来的景象
I had a vision of what was to come.
什么景象
What sort of vision?
人所带来的黑暗
The darkness of man.
我不能让历史重蹈覆辙
I won't let it happen again.
你是说我还没进娘胎  你就预见到这种景象了吗
Are you saying you had this vision before I was conceived?
过去无关紧要
The past doesn't matter.
认清当下使命
Define yourself in the present
方能统治未来
and you might rule in the future.
上帝啊
Dear God.
已经开始了
It's already begun.
什么
What?
王国无主  势必各方混战  争权逐利
With no King in place, there'll be carnage across the land.
你要做什么
What're you doing?
不管他们是谁  都应以基督之礼安葬
Whoever these men are, they deserve a Christian burial.
要拯救他们已经太迟了
They're long past saving.
亚瑟  说两句
Arthur-tell him.
此地不宜久留  否则有性命之虞
We stay here, we're a target for whoever did this.
不要操心死者了  活着的人更需要我们
Stop worrying about the dead-the living need us more!
梅林说的对  我们应该马上离开
Merlin's right. We have to get out of here.
现在帮不了他们
We can't help them now.
我们走
Let's move.
就在这里休息
We rest here.
在村里休息  这是明智之举吗
This village? Is that wise?
看看便知
We'll find out.
恐惧如瘟疫蔓延
Fear spreads like plague.
不要下马  径直骑过去
Stay on your horses and ride on through.
我们打算去海边
We are on our way to the coast.
希望今晚在这里过夜
We were hoping for shelter tonight.
这里不欢迎你们
There's no welcome here.
对老朋友也要这样吗
Not even for an old friend?
梅林  是你吗
Merlin! Is that you?
这才像话
That's more like it.
太久没见了
It's been too long.
如果你不完成使命  这些黎民百姓
It's people like these that will be next to the slaughter
就难逃厄运了
if you don't fulfill your destiny.
如果我不跟你来  你打算怎么做
What would you have done if I hadn't come with you.
有个外乡人预言你是未来的国王
A stranger says you're the future king.
也许过一晚  也许过一年
Maybe it takes a night, maybe it takes a year,
反正你拗不过好奇心  总会来的
but in the end you're too curious not to come.
你以为你有那么了解我
You think you know me that well?
我是看着你长大的
I watched you since you were a child.
讲讲我的出身吧
Tell me about my birth.
你父亲尤瑟想要一个名为伊格兰的女人
Your father, Uther, desired a woman named Igraine,
而她属于敌对的康沃尔公爵
who belonged to a rival warlord, the Duke of Cornwall.
由于无法打败对方
Unable to best his forces,
尤瑟改变了战略
Uther changed tactics
把我召了去
and summoned me.
召你做什么
To do what?
把他变为康沃尔的容貌
To change Uther to resemble Cornwall
如此便能拥有伊格兰  享一夜之欢
so he could have Igraine for just one night.
你想让我相信我是巫术与奸淫的产物
You want me to believe I'm the product of sorcery and rape?
那晚她就怀上了你
You were conceived that night.
梅林  我要真相
Merlin, I want the truth.
而不是编造出来让我相信巫术的故事
Not some story to make me believe in magic.
你相信与否  我不关心
I don't care what you believe.
很久以前我就已经放弃那些誓约了
But I've sworn off those vows a long time ago.
为什么
Why?
-因为代价  -什么代价
- Because they cost.  - Cost how?
你到底要不要我讲完
You want me to finish or not?
所以尤瑟把我给了你
So Uther gave me to you.
你就是我的报酬
You were my payment.
你为何要一个孩子作为报酬
Why would you take a child as payment?
这个国家需要一个前所未有的明君
This realm needs a leader better than any who has come before.
有尤瑟的血统  以及埃克特的教导
With Uther's blood line and Ector's guidance,
此人非你莫属
that can be you.
我知道你有疑问
I know you've got questions,
但我会在你左右  共同寻找答案
but I will be at your side and we will find the answers together.
我们要共建充满希望与荣耀的土地
We are going to build a land full of hope
让恐惧烟消云散
and honor where fear is extinguished,
循着灯塔的指引  人们从四面八方
to which people will flock from far and wide,
慕名而来
seeking out our beacon of light.
明日我们就将抵达古老的权力王座
Tomorrow we ride to an ancient seat of power.
你定能成为伟大的君主
You can be the greatest of men
统领一个伟大的王国
in the greatest of lands.
相信我  亚瑟
Trust me, Arthur.
亚瑟
Arthur!
我来了
I'm coming!
洛特王的侍卫
An outrider for King Lot.
这是洛特军队的颜色
These are Lot's colors.
你还尚未即位  就已引发战火了
You're not even installed and you're starting a war!
上马
Back on the horses!
如果他们发现我们在这儿
If we're here when they find him,
你就活不到即位之时了
you won't live to be King.
卡米洛特
Camelot.
这是个废弃的城堡
It's a ruin.
过去是罗马人建造的
The Romans built it.
而我们将在此创造未来
We'll create the future here.
此地战略位置极好  易守难攻
This has good position, strong fortifications.
无人胆敢觊觎
And no one will expect it.
没想到你是这样打算的
This is not what I thought you meant!
我还以为会有军队  武器和仆从
I thought there'd be armies, and weapons and servants!
还有美女
And girls.
肯定不会就这么寒酸吧
There has to be more than this, right?
我的意思是  至少得有钱吧
I mean, I must have money.
没有
No.
我们走的时候你怎么不说
Why didn't you say that before we left!
说了你就不会来了
You wouldn't have come.
你没说会是这种情况
You didn't say it would be like this.
你也没问
You didn't ask.
我们要为活命而战
We're in a fight for our lives,
为王国之魂而战
for the soul of this country.
来吧  大家在等着你呢
Now, there are people waiting.
卡米洛特的大殿
The Great Hall of Camelot.
见见这些已经宣誓效忠于你的人吧
Meet those who have sworn their allegiance to you.
欧菲尔斯  里昂提斯  布拉提斯  派力诺
Ulfius! Leontes! Brastias! Pelinor!
您父亲是位伟大的领袖
Your father was a great leader.
忠于您  即忠于先王
Our loyalty passes to you.
我们任您差遣
We stand at your bidding,
誓死保卫彭德拉根血统
ready to defend the Pendragon line.
我不了解尤瑟
I never knew Uther.
但他既然赢得了诸位的忠心
But if he inspired such loyalty, I am humbled
我也不能愧对于此
to stand before you and
我将尽我所能  不辱诸位的耿耿忠心
I'll do whatever I can to justify your allegiance.
听从您的吩咐
We are your servants.
这些都是你的战友
These are your allies.
而敌方人多势众  远胜于我
Your enemies are much greater in number.
这又是你早先没提醒我的事儿
Something else you forgot to mention earlier.
洛锡安及奥克尼地区的洛特王
King Lot of Lothian and Orkney.
康沃尔的新任公爵
The new Duke of Cornwall;
南特斯  苏格兰以及卡拉朵斯诸王
Kings Nentes, Scotland, and Carados.
我已要求他们来这里
I've summoned them here.
什么
You've done what?
好让他们认可
So they all can recognize you
你是尤瑟·彭德拉根的正统继承人
as the true heir of Uther Pendragon.
如果他们不认可呢
What if they don't?
必须认可
They must.
这是你的房间
These are your chambers.
我将你父亲的遗物带过来了
I had your father's effects brought here.
他是怎样的人  我的父亲
What was he like? My father.
不屈不挠
Unyielding.
仅此而已吗
That's it?
一个词就形容了他的一生
The life of a man and you take one word.
你知道这点就够了
It's all you need to know.
不  不够
No, it's not!
我想知道一切
I want to know everything.
他吃什么喝什么  怎么站怎么坐
What he ate, what he drank, how he stood.
他所爱的人  他痛苦与欢笑的缘由
Who he loved, what made him laugh or weep.
而你用一个词就打发了
And you give me one word.
其他人可以告诉你他的各种脾气性格
Anyone else can tell you his character and contradictions.
而我说的这个词是你最需要的
I gave you the word you most require.
是你必须继承的他的品质
The aspect you must take from him.
不屈不挠的强悍
An unyielding strength.
因为从现在开始  所有人都会挑战你的权威
Because from now on, everyone will challenge you,
方方面面
on everything.
你需要被肯定
You need to be certain.
如果没有呢
What if I'm not?
必须如此
You have to be.
如果我错了呢
What if I'm wrong?
绝不可能
You can't be.
还有一件事
Oh, one more thing.
尤瑟还有一个女儿
Uther also had a daughter.
你同父异母的姐姐
Your half-sister.
他在废墟中扶一个孩子即位
He installs a child in a ruin,
还指望整个王国山呼万岁
and expects the kingdom to kneel?
我认为这巫师的脑子有问题
I think the sorcerer's mind is addled.
不  他非常睿智
No, he's clever.
过去曾有一种力量
This was a power, once.
他坚信能够唤醒它
He believes he can awaken it.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我厌倦了男人们的游戏
The games of men exhaust me.
我们向来武力说话  胜者为王
We ride in strong.
这冒牌货若敢穿我父亲的长袍
If this pretender wears my father's robes,
我定要剜出他的双目
I shall gouge his eyes.
上
On!
那是你姐姐
That's your sister?
他不是
No.
他的确是尤瑟之子  我有证据
He's Uther's son. I have proof.
我父亲没有正统子嗣
My father had no legitimate son.
要是有  我一定会知道
I would have known.
说实话  我跟你一样感到诧异
Honestly, this is as strange to me as it is to you.
但当梅林...
But when Merlin-
这家伙也这么能言善辩
It talks, too.
他长相俊美  巧舌如簧
It's pretty, it talks.
但他并非继承人
But it is not an heir.
我们可以联手治国  以慰父亲在天之灵
We can work together to honor our father-
你根本不认识我父亲
You didn't know my father.
瞧瞧他  假冒得连点说服力都没有
Look at it. Not even a convincing pretender.
你并非帝王之材  只是区区一介草民
You're not made of kings, boy, but of common clay.
那巫师承诺给你多少钱
How much did the sorcerer promise you?
他没承诺我任何事
He didn't promise me anything.
你为何要这样对我
Why are you doing this to me?
此事并非私人恩怨
This isn't personal.
我这么做是为了这国家
This is for the country.
这是我与生俱来的权力
This is my birthright.
是吗
Is it?
不如问问他母亲吧
We should ask his mother,
伊格兰王后
Queen Igraine.
你并无子嗣
You were childless.
我可没这么说过
I never spoke of this.
这是其他男人的野种
This is some other man's bastard.
不是我父亲的  否则我一定会知道
Not my father's. I would have known.
可你的确不知道
And yet you didn't.
这是你生下便被我带走的男孩吗
Is this the boy I took from you when he was born?
是的  我确信无疑
Yes, I believe he is.
这就是尤瑟的儿子
This is Uther's son.
我的儿子
My son.
不是吧  去他妈的
No. Fuck this.
你以为这样就完了吗
You think this is the end of it?
梅林告诉我他把尤瑟变成了你丈夫的模样
Merlin told me he changed Uther's face to resemble your husband,
也就是康沃尔公爵
the Duke of Cornwall.
这不可能
That's not possible.
对  听来确实匪夷所思
No, it's not.
但我相信那的确发生过
But I believe it happened.
有那么一瞬间  我看着他
There was a moment, when I looked at him,
仿佛看到了另一个人
that I saw another.
我仿佛看到了尤瑟
I saw Uther.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你后来怎么会成了尤瑟的妻子
How did you then come to be Uther's wife?
尤瑟跟我在一起的那晚
That night that Uther was with me,
他的军队杀害了公爵
his forces killed the Duke.
获胜的军阀可以占有战败者的妻子
The vanquishing warlord can claim the victim's wife.
我能活下来已是幸事
I was lucky to live.
但你怀了我
But you were pregnant with me.
你放弃了我
You gave me up.
是梅林把你从我怀里抢走的
Merlin tore you from my arms.
你就从没想起过我吗
Didn't you ever think of me?
每天清晨醒来  我首先想到的就是你
You were my first thought each morning.
我观察每个男孩的脸庞  希望有一个是你
I studied every boy's face, hoping for you.
我被禁止去找你
I was forbidden to search for you.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
亚瑟
Arthur.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yes.
她怎么样  一切还好吗
What was she like? How was it?
还行
Fine.
这就完了
That's it?
走  我们去探索一下
Come on, let's explore.
上去看看  走
Let's look up here. Come on.
看
Here,
瞧瞧这个
look at this.
此堡垒由马格纳斯·昆塔斯
Magnus Quintus
修建于
built this fort
瓦伦蒂诺二世统治第六年
in the sixth year of the reign of the Emperor Valentinio the Second.
他完成了一半工事
He who has begun has the work half done.
如果你看到这里的全貌  就不会这么说了
You wouldn't say that if you saw the state of the place now.
想象一下这里当初的盛况吧
Think of what it must have been like back then.
今后也有可能再现当年的辉煌
Or what it can be again.
你跟踪我们
Have you been following us?
这是梅林的指示
Merlin's instructions.
我得保护你的安全
I'm to keep you safe.
保护我还是确保我不会离开
Keep me safe or make sure I don't leave?
两者皆有吧
Bit of both.
要是我逃跑了呢
What if I make a run for it?
为什么要跑  你在这里应有尽有
Why would you? You've got everything here.
这里有如此多的....潜力
There's so much-potential.
你的语气很像梅林
You sound like Merlin.
我相信他所做的一切
I believe in what he's doing.
他带你来这里一定有他的原因
Why he brought you here.
所以你即使没见过我  也肯盲目跟从他
So you followed him blindly even though you hadn't met me.
不  不是盲从
No, not blindly.
我们很多人一直觉得  仅仅是战斗还不够
Some of us have always felt it's not enough just to fight;
大家需要一个为之战斗的理由
there has to be a cause worth fighting for.
梅林告诉我们可以建成何等伟业
Merlin's told us what's possible, what can be built here
只要有你和你的王室血脉
with you and your breed of king.
我怎么可能在一夜之间担起此重任
How do I become that overnight?
相信你的本能
Trust your instincts.
我可没有当国王的本能
My instincts aren't that of a king.
万一你只是尚未发掘呢
What if they are and you just don't know it yet?
她是谁
Who is she?
你干嘛啊
What're you doing?!
她是谁
Who is she?
我不知道
I don't know!
亚瑟  你最好来看看
Arthur! You'd better see this.
他们都是冲着你来的
This is all for you.
天啊  帮帮我吧
God help me.
现在怎么办
What do we do now?
别怯场
Show no fear.
大胆地说
Speak boldly.
像国王一样回应他们
Answer them as their king.
没什么好担心的  对吧
Nothing to worry about, right?
你预见过未来  我会成为国王
I mean, you've had visions. I'm going to be king.
一切都会好的  这是命定的  是有保证的
Everything's going to be fine. It's fate. It's guaranteed.
-不  -不
- No. - No?
如果你死了  幻象会改变
If you die, the visions will change.
个人宿命可以依靠祈求
Fate can go begging.
天命大势却要自己赢得
Destiny has to be won.
此刻过后  一切都将不同以往了  亚瑟
Nothing can ever be the same after this moment, Arthur.
现在离开  你还能保住小命
Leave now and salvage your life.
执意留下  你将会失去一切
Stay, and you'll lose everything.
你寡不敌众
You're outnumbered.
别成为一个巫师的傀儡
Don't be a sorcerer's figurehead.
回家去吧
Go home.
说话啊  你个乳臭未干的杂种
Speak, y'beardless bastard!
这里是我的地盘
You stand in my hall
是我的王土  你们给我放尊重点
in my realm and you will show me respect!
我是尤瑟先王货真价实的正统子嗣
I am the true and legitimate heir to Uther's throne.
你们得发誓效忠于我
And you will pledge your allegiance to me,
否则后果自负
or suffer for it.
懂吗  你个胡子拉碴的白痴
Understand that, y'bearded fool?
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
带他进来
Bring him in.
这是我儿子  我的长子
That's my son. My eldest son.
你杀了他
And you killed him.
当天树林里有两个侍卫
There were two outriders in the woods that day.
活下来的那个目睹了一切
The other one saw it all.
他袭击了我
He attacked me.
不  你个混蛋
No! You bastard!
这阻止不了任何事
This stops nothing-
我并非禽兽
I'm not a monster.
给你们五天时间
Five dawns I'll give you.
让他哀悼五天  然后离开
Five dawns for him to grieve and then be gone.
如果你们不走  会有更多的人牺牲
But if you don't leave, there will be more slaughter.
拦住他
Stop him!
拦住他  拦住他  拦住他...
Stop him! Stop him! Stop him! Stop-
对不起  我很遗憾
I'm sorry-I'm sorry-
梅林  你对我做了什么  放开我
Merlin, what have you done to me? Get off!
你对我做了什么
What have you done to me?